MAN:
Police found her in the street.
Looks like she was bitten
by some kind of an animal.
WOMAN: Jesus. Her water's broken.
She's going into uterine contractions.
We have to do a C-section.
[BABY CRYING]
[EKG FLATLINING]
- What you got down there, little man?
- That's my heat-seeker.
I'll bet it is.
[SQUEALS]
[LAUGHS]
- So where we going?
- It's a surprise, baby.
Yeah, I like surprises. Yeah.
Oh, my God.
What the fuck are we doing here?
Whoo. Look at all that.
[LAUGHS]
What the fuck is that?
Hey.
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
What did you just say?
[DANCE MUSIC PLAYING]
OVER SPEAKERS]
Wow.
Hey, what's up? Oh, man.
Whoo! All right.
Yeah. Whoo!
[LAUGHING]
What's happening?
[GRUNTS]
Hey, man.
Fuck.
Fuck, I need a drink.
No. No.
What's wrong, baby?
[HISSES]
[SCREAMING]
No!
[GROWLING AND HISSING]
Oh, no.
MAN 1:
Shut up, man.
WOMAN: Is that him?
MAN 2: Jesus, it's him.
MAN 3:
It's the Day Walker.
Come on, Day Walker!
[VAMPIRES SCREAMING]
[SCREAMING]
Hey! I'm gonna rip
your fucking head off.
- Look out! Hey, out of the way!
- Get out of there!
That's him. That's him.
Get him. Fuck him up.
We're gonna jack you up.
Make him hurt bad. Whoo!
[YELLING]
[QUINN SPEAKING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Quinn...
...I'm getting a little tired
of chopping you up.
Thought I might try fire, for a change.
Give my regards to Frost.
No, please. Please don't.
MAN 1:
Over here, sergeant.
- Put him out.
- Yes, sir.
MAN 2:
Paramedics, coming through.
Got a charred cadaver here for you.
It's still warm too.
One, two, three.
Oh, Jesus, that's rank.
MAN: Paramedics said he was
still screaming when they found him...
...stapled to a wall.
CURTIS:
That's very pretty.
CURTIS: Did you check the chem panel?
Blood sugar's three times the norm.
Phosphorus and uric acid
are off the charts.
KAREN:
You took this off a DOA?
Yeah.
But this doesn't make any sense.
The red blood cells are biconvex,
which is impossible.
Look at the polys, they're binucleated.
- Okay, Curtis, it's 3:00 in the morning...
- This is not a joke.
I've got the body sitting in the morgue
right now.
I thought you promised
to give me some distance.
I just want you to come down
and take a look.
Okay. Show me the body.
And I don't wanna hear
a word about us.
Done. We've had that conversation.
You haven't started
on the internal organs yet?
No, just a blood sample
through the pericardium.
The maxilla looks a little deformed.
There's some odd muscle structure
around the canines.
I'm gonna go ahead start the Y
and check the tracheal mucosa.
Let me ask you something.
Honestly.
You ever have second thoughts
about us?
Sometimes.
But then I remember
how much of an asshole you were.
You wanna cut me some slack here?
You asked for some time off,
I gave you some time off.
- Look, Curtis, it's over.
- I'm trying. Really, I am.
[GASPING]
MAN 1: Call security!
MAN 2: Get back!
Came back to finish you off.
Get out of my way, you freak.
Freeze!
Motherfucker,
are you out of your damn mind?
[SCREAMING]
MAN 1: He's there, right there.
MAN 2: Go ahead.
- Go.
MAN 3: Hey, you, freeze.
MAN 4: Come on. Come on.
MAN 5: Fire.
MAN 6:
Keep going. Keep going.
MAN 7:
Come back out.
MAN 3: Go.
MAN 7: He can't get out.
[SCREAMING]
- Freeze!
MAN 1: Hold it right there.
MAN 2: Don't do it.
MAN 3: Hey, hey...
KAREN:
My shoulder...
...is dislocated.
[YELLS]
[MACHINERY BUZZING]
[OVER SPEAKERS]
I feel rivers overflowing
BLADE:
Whistler.
[MUSIC STOPS]
WHISTLER:
Bringing home strays now?
She's been bitten.
Should've killed her, then.
Yeah, I know...
...but I didn't.
You watch her close.
She starts to turn, you finish her off.
Or I will.
She's borderline.
Another hour,
she'd be well into the change.
Dr. Karen Jenson, listen close.
I'm gonna inject you
with allium sativum. Garlic.
This is gonna hurt a lot.
It was Quinn.
Frost's little errand boy?
- You get a lead on him?
- No.
WHISTLER:
Too bad.
[GRUNTS]
Hold her.
I give her fifty-fifty,
if she makes it through the night.
Blade, the Day Walker.
Still pursuing his ridiculous crusade.
How many died?
We don't have an exact count.
Apparently, he used a lot of silver.
- We're having difficulty...
- Send in Frost.
Deacon Frost.
You can come in now.
[IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
These nightclubs of yours
are dangerous.
Are they?
They draw needless attention
to our kind. You know our policy.
Your policy, not mine.
DRAGONETTI:
Our livelihood...
...depends on our ability to blend in...
...on our discretion.
Maybe it's time
we forgot about discretion.
We should be ruling the humans...
...not running around
making back-alley treaties with them.
For fuck's sake,
these people are our food not our allies.
- You're out of line, Frost.
- Am I?
Maybe I'm just the first to say out loud
what we've all been thinking.
We have existed this way
for thousands of years.
Who are you to challenge our ways?
You're not even a pureblood.
Like it matters.
I was born a vampire...
...as was every other member
of this house.
But, you, Frost...
...you were merely turned.
The world belongs to us,
not the humans.
You know that.
Do we have any other business
to discuss?
Well, there's the matter of our offshore
accounts. We're having difficulty...
And have you made the transfer...?
Gaetano, you may wake up one day
and find yourself extinct.
[BELL RINGS]
- You're a week early.
- Yeah.
Whistler says I'm building up
a resistance to the serum.
Yeah, I figured that might happen.
You take care, all right?
WHISTLER: I must be getting soft
in my old age...
...letting you bring home
a stray like that.
It was damn stupid of you.
You might have lucked out though.
I checked her background.
Turns out she's a hematologist.
She might be useful to us.
BLADE:
I doubt it.
WHISTLER:
I'm serious.
I took a look at that notebook of hers.
She's on to something.
I had to increase the dose.
It's over 50 milligrams now.
That's getting dangerous.
Just do it, old man.
Wander off the beaten path, doctor?
Who are you people?
My name's Abraham Whistler.
You've met Blade.
So am I a prisoner here?
Not at all.
We just had to take certain precautions
before we let you go.
You gotta understand,
they're everywhere.
Vampires.
The Hominis nocturna.
We hunt them, you see.
Moving from one city to the next
tracking their migrations.
They're hard to kill.
- They tend to regenerate.
- And I'm supposed to believe all this?
Well, you already met Mr. Crispy
at the hospital.
What do you think?
So, what do you use, then?
Stakes? Crosses?
Crosses don't do squat.
Some of the legends are true, though.
Vampires are severely allergic to silver.
Feed them garlic
and they go into anaphylactic shock.
Then, of course, there's always sunlight,
ultraviolet rays.
I got this sucker running.
You wanna give it a try tonight?
Still heavy.
But you're so big.
If you wanna live to see another day,
you'll be out of town by nightfall.
So where am I supposed to go?
You've been exposed to them.
One way or another,
somebody's gonna take you out.
There's a war going on out there.
Blade, myself, a few others...
...we've tried to keep it
from spilling over onto the streets...
...but sometimes, people like yourself
get caught in the crossfire.
I have blood samples.
I can go to the police.
They own the police.
You have to understand,
they're everywhere.
Chances are you've seen them yourself
and didn't know it.
On the subway or in a bar.
So that's it?
You guys just patch me up
and send me on my way.
Here. Vampire Mace.
Silver nitrate, essence of garlic.
You keep your eyes open.
Be careful.
One other thing...
...buy yourself a gun.
If you start getting sensitive
to daylight...
...if you find you're thirsty, regardless
of how much you've had to drink...
...then I suggest you take that gun
and use it on yourself.
Better that than the alternative.
[DANCE MUSIC PLAYING
ON HEADPHONES]
You have been warned before.
These archives are restricted
to the members of the House of Erebus.
You are wasting your time.
It's a dead language.
The ancient texts
can never be translated.
You wouldn't even understand them.
Damn it, Frost, I'm talking to you!
Shh.
Keep your voice down, Gaetano.
[MUSIC STOPS]
We're in a library.
You don't need to shout.
What are you up to, Frost?
What are you gonna do? Hm?
What?
You bore me.
BLADE:
Remember what we told you.
You keep your eyes open.
They're everywhere.
But it's daytime.
MAN 1: Hey, hey, hey, that's mine.
MAN 2: Spare some change?
MAN 3: Anything else?
WOMAN: No, that's it.
How you doing?
I'm sorry. Whoa, whoa! Hold on.
Hold on. Hold on. I'm a police officer.
I'm sorry, okay? Police officer.
I didn't mean to scare you.
- The front door was open.
- What are you doing in here?
I'm just here on a routine check.
Look, I'm Officer Krieger,
42nd Precinct.
You're Karen Jenson, right?
Yeah.
Your co-workers at the hospital said
that you were kidnapped last night.
Are you okay?
KAREN: What happened
to the other doctor I was with?
Curtis Webb, he died.
No, look, don't worry about that
right now, okay?
- Why?
- Because you're dead too, bitch.
[GROANING]
Son of a bitch, what is this?
What is this, garlic?
Yeah, well,
he said it would work against vampires.
Vampires?
Who said I was a vampire, huh?
Nobody.
He's a familiar.
A vampire wannabe.
If he's loyal enough...
...and he proves himself,
maybe his master will turn him.
Wait a minute. You used me as bait?
Get over it.
Is all that necessary?
BLADE:
That's a glyph, a vampire cattle brand.
It means Officer Krieger here
is somebody's property.
Another vampire tries to bleed
this little hooker...
...then they have to answer
to his owner.
Deacon Frost.
We've been tracking him for a long time.
All right, Officer Krieger, you gonna be
a good little bloodhound, huh?
Tell us what your master's been up to?
Great, now you're robbing him.
You gonna rob me too?
How do you think that
we fund this organization, huh?
We're not exactly the March of Dimes.
It's fake.
Well, looks like our friend here's
been blood running.
Hillburn Clinic.
I know this place, it's a blood bank.
BLADE: Owned by vampires,
and there's one in every city.
And they always deliver.
So where were you taking it?
I don't know what you're talking...
Look, take it easy.
I'm only gonna ask you one more time.
Where were you taking it?
Go fuck yourself.
- Fuck me? No, you suck this.
- No, look.
Get out of the way.
WOMAN:
Oh, my God.
Look, right over there.
You better wake up.
The world you live in
is just a sugarcoated topping.
There is another world beneath it,
the real world.
And if you wanna survive it,
you'd better learn to pull the trigger.
KAREN:
Wait a minute. I'm coming with you.
You're useless.
I have to stick with you.
It's the only way that I'll stay alive
long enough to find a cure for myself.
There is no cure.
He's not gonna come back.
Nobody's that stupid.
When you understand
the nature of a thing...
...you know what it's capable of.
[CAR ENGINE STARTS]
- It's Krieger. I'm at 16009.
MAN [OVER RADIO]: Yes?
KRIEGER: Get me Pearl.
- Pearl is feeding.
I got a delivery from Frost here
and I just had a run-in with Blade.
We've gotta clear out
that clinic on Hillburn now.
BLADE: Looks like we hit pay dirt.
That's a vampire mark.
It means there's a safe house
around here somewhere.
A place they can go if dawn is coming.
See the valets over there?
They're vampires.
So is the doorman.
And the whore on the corner.
- How can you tell?
BLADE: By the way they move.
The way they smell.
KAREN:
It's like a bad dream.
There's worse things out tonight
than vampires.
- Like what?
- Like me.
Okay, Vampire Anatomy 101.
Crosses and running water don't do dick,
forget what you've seen in movies.
You use a stake, silver, or sunlight.
You know how to use one of these?
- No, but I damn sure learn quick.
- Safety's off, round's chambered.
Silver hollow-point filled with garlic.
Aim for the head or the heart.
Anything else is your ass.
[SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Do you have an invitation?
[DANCE MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS]
[SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Kenji.
[GRUNTING]
Where's the entrance?
I can't tell you that, man, if...
I'm gonna ask you one more time.
Where's the entrance?
Okay. Look, it's in the freezer.
Come on, man, I told you!
It's in the fridge!
- Okay.
- You give Frost a message from me.
You tell him it's open season
on all suck-heads.
Some kind of archive.
This must be where
they keep most of their records.
KAREN:
Isn't this just a little high-tech?
They've got their claws into everything.
Politics, finance, real estate.
They already own half of downtown.
[CHATTERING]
MAN 1: Hey, how's it going?
MAN 2: I'm surprised they were there.
Frost throws a good party.
Yeah, but where is he?
Come on, baby.
Don't keep everyone waiting.
MAN [OVER SPEAKER]: Deacon,
there's someone here to see you.
KRIEGER:
I gotta talk to you, Frost.
I'm sorry. I had to come here.
It's a mistake going to Pearl's.
I know that. Dumb fucking me.
- I know you're disappointed.
- Am I that transparent?
- You wanna meet him?
- Yeah.
I can get you guys in with him,
we're tight. We're like brothers.
Fuck. Frost...
- Hey.
- Yeah.
Deac, Deac, I've been telling
these bitches all about you, man.
They've been dying to meet you.
They are so psyched,
these badass bitches. I meet them...
- Nice.
- Deac?
Frost, it's about Blade.
He's busy.
When he's focused on something...
...he doesn't have time to fuck around.
KRIEGER: Frost, this is important.
Blade was waiting for me.
Look, they're using the girl as bait.
- And you were stupid enough to take it.
- Shut up, bitch.
I didn't know he was gonna be there.
It was a trap, see?
But don't worry, it's no problem.
We can still get the girl.
Yeah.
- Whoo!
MAN: Yeah.
WOMAN 1:
Oh, come on.
- Oh, yes.
WOMAN 2: All right.
Forget the girl. I want Blade.
MERCURY:
I know you do.
FROST:
You hear me, Quinn? I want him alive.
What?
Wait a minute, man.
You want him alive?
KAREN:
What's that smell?
MAN:
Study the image carefully, Frost.
You will need 12 purebloods
to make the ritual work.
Krieger, is that you?
He's here. He's here.
BLADE:
This must be Pearl, the record keeper.
[FARTING]
He's here.
He's going to kill me.
You need me, Frost. You need me.
Pearl, you're history.
Have the good grace
to die with some fucking dignity.
PEARL:
Frost, you useless bloodsucker.
FROST: Congratulations, Blade.
- Frost.
I hear you've been looking for me.
I'm flattered.
It'll pass.
Fuck.
- What is that?
- That, biscuit boy, is a UV lamp.
We're gonna play a little game
of 20 questions.
Depending on how you answer,
you may walk out of here with a tan.
What's that?
Oh, that? Oh, it's nothing.
It's routine research.
Actually, it's a video game.
[PEARL SCREAMING]
That must have hurt.
- It's a fragment, a piece of the prophecy.
- What prophecy?
Oh, I'm not really sure.
There's so many. How could I...?
[IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
And there is nothing you can do about it,
Day Walker!
Is that so?
Well, that's what Frost says.
Then you won't mind me borrowing this
for a while, will you?
If he moves, fry him.
What's in here?
Nothing. It's a storeroom.
You're wasting your time.
There's nothing of importance
to anyone.
- Then you won't mind if I take a peek.
- No!
He moved.
KAREN:
What is this?
BLADE: These are the pages
from the Book of Erebus.
The vampire Bible.
It contains everything...
...their entire history.
La Magra must be one of their legends.
Why is Frost so interested
in La Magra?
Shh!
[FOOTSTEPS PATTERING]
Give me your hand.
[QUINN SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
QUINN:
Do you remember me?
Give it to him!
Hey. Hey! Nice one.
Well, well, well.
You took my arm, man.
Remember? But it's cool.
I got a new one.
Think I'll ever play piano again?
You can slice him, you can dice him,
but the Quinn man just keeps on coming.
Check it out. I've got his pig-sticker.
You're a fuckup, Crease.
You're a fuckup. "I got his pig-sticker."
You're just full of surprises,
ain't you, chief?
Stay away from me, sweetness...
...because I'm not finished
with you yet.
Lookie here.
Silver. Nice craftsmanship, huh?
Probably cost you a pretty penny.
Now, this here is a man
who takes his job...
...just a little too seriously,
don't you think?
Come to think of it, Blade,
I owe you one.
Actually, if you wanna get technical,
Blade...
...I owe you two.
[LAUGHING]
What's so funny, bright eyes?
I'm expecting company.
[WHISTLER SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY OVER EARPIECE]
Catch you fuckers at a bad time?
No, no guns!
No, no, no! You idiots!
No, fuck him. Get Blade!
You asshole!
MAN 1: Move it!
MAN 2: Hurry up.
Idiots, stop it, now! I need him!
Deac wants Blade alive! Go!
KAREN:
You've been listening the whole time?
BLADE:
Radio contact.
WHISTLER: Think I'd let him run loose
without a chaperone?
Christ, I'm too old for this.
Somebody get me
a goddamn wheelchair.
Whistler.
He can take care of himself. Jump.
[BUZZING]
[RUMBLING]
[TRAIN HORN HONKING]
[QUINN SCREAMING]
What are you gonna do?
Oh, my God.
What's wrong?
It's dislocated.
Let me help you.
[GROANS]
- Here, let me give you a hand...
- No. Get away.
You're one of them, aren't you?
No. I'm something else.
WHISTLER:
I found him when he was 13.
He'd been living on the streets,
feeding off the homeless.
His need for blood
had taken hold at puberty.
I took him for a vampire at first.
Almost killed him too.
Then I realized what he was.
Blade's mother was attacked
by a vampire while she was pregnant.
She died, but he lived.
Unfortunately,
he'd undergone certain genetic changes.
He can withstand garlic, silver,
even sunlight.
And he's got their strength.
This time tomorrow,
all those wounds of his will be healed.
He still ages like a human, though.
See, vampires age slower than us.
Unfortunately,
he also inherited their thirst.
KAREN: I thought the serum
was supposed to suppress that.
Time's running out.
His body's starting to reject it.
So far, all my efforts
to find a cure have failed.
Why do you hunt them?
I had a family once.
A wife, two daughters.
Then a drifter came calling one evening.
A vampire.
He toyed with them first.
Tried to make me decide
which order they'd die in.
We kill as many of them as we can find,
but it's getting worse.
Because of Frost.
There's something happening
in the vampire ranks.
It's something big.
And I'd stake my life
that son of a bitch is at the center of it.
KAREN:
Blade?
Whistler told me what happened.
He told me what you are.
You don't know me.
You don't know anything about me.
I'm not human.
You look human to me...
Humans don't drink blood.
That was a long time ago.
Maybe you should let that go.
I have spent my whole life looking
for that thing that killed my mother...
...and made me what I am.
And every time
I take one of those monsters out...
...I get a little piece of that life back.
So don't you tell me about forgetting.
QUINN:
My fault? He took us by surprise!
Two of them against
your entire security force?
Don't put that shit on me,
you were there too.
I'm sure Deacon will appreciate
our cutback in payroll.
QUINN: Ow! You little skeez.
- The amputee lifestyle really suits you.
I should put this stump
through that grin.
Face it, angel. You were sloppy.
You got what you deserved.
QUINN:
Deac, let me take this guy out, man.
Look what he fucking did!
He took my hand again!
Listen to me. I want him alive.
QUINN:
What the fuck are you talk...?
You want him alive? We've been trying
to kill this motherfucker for years.
Are you out of your fucking mind?
You want...?
Shh. Big guy, relax.
Be patient.
We got a lot to do here.
I need you, man.
- I need you.
- Yeah.
FROST:
Good morning.
How you feeling?
Look at that.
Ooh! Getting a little toasty
out here, huh?
When was the last time you stopped
to appreciate a good sunrise?
That's right, you were born a vampire,
so you never had the pleasure, have you?
That's okay. It's all right.
At least we're here together.
Share the moment.
Which means a lot to me
by the way, really.
I mean that.
Because actually,
when you get to know me...
...I'm a fairly sentimental type of guy.
Bit of an innocent, you might say.
Do what you want, Frost.
Doesn't make any difference.
You just don't fucking get it.
- You're never gonna be a pureblood.
- Hold him.
DRAGONETTI:
You will never rule us.
[DRAGONETTI GROANING]
Jesus Christ. Have a nice day.
Sorry, you old dog. You just got
a little too long in the teeth.
[LAUGHING]
What, man? That was funny.
"Long, tooth." It's funny, man.
Did I tell you the one
about the leprechaun...?
[SCREAMING]
What have you done with Dragonetti?
Let's get down to business, shall we?
I need 12 volunteers.
BLADE:
Whistler.
WHISTLER:
What is this?
Smells like a vampire
wiped his ass with it.
I took it from the archives.
WHISTLER: It's written in blood.
BLADE: It's from the Book of Erebus.
I think it's what Frost
has been working on.
WHISTLER: It's something about
the blood god, the Spirits of the 12.
I don't know.
I can't make out the rest of it.
Well, maybe this'll help.
We'll figure out something.
BLADE:
So, what's all of this?
Took a trip to the hospital last night,
borrowed some equipment.
For your miracle cure?
KAREN:
This is EDTA. It's an anticoagulant.
We use it to treat blood clots.
Look what happens when I introduce it
onto a sample of vampire blood.
Take a step back.
The reaction's energetic.
- Some cure.
KAREN: I didn't say EDTA was a cure.
But maybe you could use it
to explode some vampire heads.
Wait a minute.
I need a sample of your blood.
Later. I gotta go downtown.
- I need some serum.
WHISTLER: Serum can wait.
This is important.
[COUGHING]
- Is he sick?
- Cancer.
You have a lot of love for him,
don't you?
We have a good arrangement.
He makes the weapons, I use them.
You know, my mother used to say,
"A cold heart is a dead heart."
You don't look so good.
I'm just a little tired.
You know, we've been working all night.
I guess we didn't catch it in time.
You got another day, two at the most.
For what it's worth, I'm sorry.
You make it sound like
I'm already dead.
FROST:
Blade.
How you doing, chief?
Easy.
Wouldn't want our little friend here...
...to wind up on the back
of a milk carton, would we?
It's nice to finally meet you, man.
Had my eye on you for years.
I know all about you.
Your serum, Whistler, everything.
Sunblock.
Hey, it's a start, right?
The goal, of course, is to be like you.
A Day Walker.
You got the best of both worlds,
don't you?
All our strengths,
none of our weaknesses.
Well, maybe I don't see it that way.
Oh, so it's back to pretending
we're human again?
Come on.
Spare me the Uncle Tom routine, okay?
You can't keep denying
what you are, man.
You think the humans will ever accept
a half-breed like you? They can't.
They're afraid of you.
And they should be. You're an animal.
You're a fucking maniac.
Look at them. They're cattle.
Pieces of meat.
What difference does it make
how their world ends?
Plague, war, famine.
Morality doesn't even enter into it.
We're just a function
of natural selection, man. The new race.
Looks like your mascara's running.
I'm offering you a truce.
I want you with us.
What, do you think I'm stupid?
[IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
You're familiar with the blood god.
[IN ENGLISH]
Frost...
...you're nothing to me...
...but another dead vampire.
You're an idiot, you know that?
I came down here
offering you an easy way out...
...and you spit it right back
in my fucking face.
Careful.
What do I care?
They're nothing but cattle,
just like you said.
If you wanna take the hard road,
be my guest, pal.
But I promise you,
by the time this is over...
...you're gonna wish they never cut you
from your mother's womb.
[SCREAMING]
Go home.
It's simple.
Why do vampires need to drink blood?
Because their own blood
can't sustain hemoglobin.
Right. So it's a genetic defect
just like hemolytic anemia.
That means that we have to treat it
with gene therapy.
Rewrite the victim's DNA
with a retrovirus.
They've been using it
on sickle-cell anemia.
Are you sure that's safe?
I have no idea,
but I don't have a choice, do I?
You actually think this could work?
On me? Yes.
On Blade, I'm not so sure.
See, he didn't contract vampirism
from a bite like I did.
He was born with it.
It's part of his DNA.
I'm sure I can cure his thirst,
but it's gonna take time.
We're out of time.
You saw what was on that disk.
[QUINN LAUGHING]
Damn.
Get out of here.
[YELLS]
I said, get out of here.
Nice place. Took us a while to find it.
- Bite me and get it over with.
- I ain't gonna bite you.
Do your thing.
Whistler?
Frost took her.
Listen to me.
The disk...
...we decoded it.
Frost is trying to trigger
a fucking vampire apocalypse.
There's some kind of...
...vampire god he's trying to resurrect.
La Magra.
You're the key.
He needs your blood.
The blood of the Day Walker.
You're the chosen one.
Listen to me, Blade.
- You can't go after him.
- Bullshit.
If Frost gets his hands on you,
it's all over.
There'll be armies
of the motherfuckers.
Shit.
You're gonna have to finish me off.
Don't want me coming back.
We can treat the wounds.
It's too far gone.
You know that.
Give me your gun.
No.
Give me the goddamn gun.
Now walk away,
you stupid son of a bitch.
Walk the fuck away.
[GUNSHOT]
By the time you watch this,
your friend Whistler should be dead.
If it makes any difference to you,
he put up quite a fight.
You can find us
at the Edgewood Towers.
You seem a bit tense.
A bit pent-up maybe,
like you need to release something.
No?
Blade not... giving it to you maybe?
I don't know, I just...
I see such a beautiful woman.
Great skin.
I'd like to see you happy, that's all.
Is this the part
where you offer to turn me?
Well, it's either that or a body bag.
Go ahead. Bite me.
I'll just cure myself.
I did it before, and I can do it again.
- There is no cure, baby.
- There is if you've been bitten.
If you were once human.
How'd you get that scar, Deacon?
A born vampire would have the power
to regenerate from birth.
You must've gotten scarred
before you were turned.
Isn't that right?
Vampires like you aren't a species.
You're just infected, a virus,
a sexually-transmitted disease...
I'll tell you what we are, sister.
We're the top of the fucking food chain.
The blood god's coming...
...and after tonight,
you people are fucking history.
He's a hurricane, an act of God.
Anyone caught in his path
will instantly be turned.
Everyone you've ever known...
...everyone you've ever fucking loved.
It won't matter who's pureblood
and who's not.
How you gonna cure
the whole fucking world?
And Blade's blood is the key.
We've got an intruder.
[ELEVATOR DINGS]
[MOTOR REVVING]
[TIRES SQUEALING]
I don't think you understand.
This dude is bad.
He had 20 guys around him...
I was there.
- He's got shit he throws...
- He's got the sword and shit.
Yeah, he can throw it in the air,
catch it underneath. Shut the fuck up!
MAN [ON RADIO]: There's no
entrance or exits where we are.
Make it happen, all right?
It's one guy on foot.
Get him! Get him! Go!
That's him, get him!
Why am I hearing gunfire? Huh?
Did I tell anybody to start shooting?
I need him alive.
MAN 1:
No.
Please. I just work for them.
- Jesus Christ. Lock this place down.
MAN 2: Yes, sir.
[SCREAMING]
Eric?
But you died.
I came back, Eric.
That very same night.
And Deacon welcomed me
into his arms.
[GRUNTING]
Jesus Christ.
I thought you'd be happy.
You're finally being reunited
with your mother, and you act like this?
Blade, give it up. It's over.
She belongs to me, buddy.
Don't look so surprised.
You spent your whole life looking
for the vampire who bit your mother.
Well, here I am.
Who would have ever guessed
you'd survive your mother's death?
But you did, and here we are...
...one big happy fucking family.
I need my serum.
Maybe when we get out of this,
I'll take that miracle cure of yours.
KAREN:
There's one catch.
If it works...
...you'll lose your strength
and your ability to regenerate.
You'll be completely human.
[GRUNTS]
Come here. Get up, damn it.
FROST:
Blade, Karen, glad you could make it.
Hey, man. Thanks for the shades.
Our ancestors called this place
the Temple of Eternal Night.
Nice, isn't it?
Apparently,
these geniuses forgot it ever existed.
Fortunately for us...
...I'm what you might call
a student of history.
Why are we here?
This temple was built
for one glorious moment:
This night, for the blood god.
Thanks.
Let's see this sword of yours.
Titanium, right? Acid-etched?
I could get used to a weapon like this.
What? You look surprised.
I told you, Blade,
I know everything about you.
Hold out your arm, Quinn.
Why, man?
Because they're, like, all better.
Hold out your arm. Now.
QUINN:
Deac, I...
Just kidding.
He was fucking with me, man.
He was, like, fucking with me.
Blade.
- Blade.
- He can't hear you, honey.
The thirst has got him now.
What do we have here?
The precious serum.
How long's it been since you shot up?
Twelve, 13 hours maybe?
I bet you're just dying for a drink,
aren't you?
What's it feel like?
Is your blood on fire?
Try some.
You might like it.
Thanks, but I prefer the real thing.
In any event, I don't think
you'll be needing these anymore.
It's a shame, you know?
When I think of what you've become...
...what you should have become.
I guess I don't blame you. I mean,
with everything that's happened...
...it's the human side of you
that's made you weak.
- You should've listened to your blood.
- You can say what you want...
...but I promise you,
you'll be dead by dawn.
Ooh.
[QUINN LAUGHING]
Get him out of here.
Get these fucks downstairs. Now.
- Come on. Let's go. Let's go.
- Come on, now.
MAN:
Come on.
Don't worry, sweetheart.
We haven't forgotten about you.
Oh, no, baby. We got something
real special planned for you.
QUINN: Found me a surfer boy
with a nice ass and I sucked him dry.
- And you'd figure he'd turn, right?
- But he didn't turn, did he?
No, he turned into some kind of zombie.
It happens sometimes, cutie.
QUINN: He was fucking tripped out.
FROST: Pathetic.
QUINN: These guys are complete scum,
man. They'll eat anything.
Animals, rodents, corpses,
and sometimes...
...they'll even eat vampires.
That's a plus.
And bearing that all in mind, I'd like
you to meet an old friend of yours.
[KAREN GRUNTING]
It's too bad. I kind of liked her.
What a waste.
[CURTIS GROANS]
CURTIS:
I don't know what's happening to me.
No pulse.
And, of course,
there's the question of lividity.
Curtis?
Karen?
Karen.
I never thought I would see you again.
Tell me, Karen, do you ever have
second thoughts about us?
[GROWLS]
Karen.
Karen!
You poor child.
You're so sick.
So thirsty.
Don't touch me.
Eric, look at me.
Vampires are my people now.
I'm one of them.
Can't be.
Yes, it can.
Try to understand, Eric.
Your mother died a long time ago.
I've hunted.
I've killed.
And I've enjoyed it.
Haven't you?
I know you have.
Sooner or later, the thirst always wins.
Come on.
Spread them out.
One on each glyph, under the tombs.
Make it perfect.
FROST:
Bring the elevator up.
MAN:
You stupid girl.
What do you think is going to happen?
La Magra? The blood god?
That's nothing more than a fairy tale
for pretty little vampires.
Then why are you sweating,
pureblood?
Are you afraid
we're gonna steal your soul?
Your pureblood spirit?
You should be. Read the prophecy.
It's time you fucks contributed
something to the cause.
Even if Frost is right,
you really think he cares about you?
You're gonna die
just like the rest of us.
Blade.
Tonight, the Age of Man
comes to an end.
No more compromises.
We're gonna be gods.
- Of course we are.
- Yeah.
I'm gonna be naughty.
I'm gonna be a naughty vampire god.
I'm right here.
Gotta stop...
- Stop the...
- Save your strength.
Flow.
You're hypovolemic.
You're bleeding to death.
Need serum.
Blade.
Listen to me.
I want you to take some of my blood.
No.
Look, just do it.
[IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Is everybody thirsty?
I hope you're all very fucking thirsty.
KAREN:
Oh, please. Please, stop.
Stop.
Oh, God.
Don't stop.
[YELLS]
How was it?
[GROWLING]
Eric, I'm your mother.
You wouldn't hurt your mother...
...would you?
Come here.
It's you and me.
I must release you.
[SCREAMING]
Fuck!
[GRUNTING]
MERCURY: Deacon?
FROST: Not anymore.
Frost.
FROST: Kill him.
- Wait. I owe you, man.
I got two new hands, Blade.
I don't know which one to use
to kill you with.
[YELLS]
Frost.
Frost!
I'm really going to enjoy this now.
FROST:
Hey, Blade.
Let's do this.
[MOUTHS]
What the fuck?
You're too late, Blade.
My turn.
Look at you. You're a little bitch.
What, your serum?
Can't help you now, stud.
Nice shot.
Some motherfuckers
are always trying to ice skate uphill.
[SCREAMING]
KAREN:
Blade.
Let's get out of here.
I need to get back to the lab
if I'm gonna cure you.
It's not over.
You keep your cure.
There's still a war going on,
and I have a job to do.
You wanna help?
Make me a better serum.
WOMAN [IN RUSSIAN]:
MAN [IN RUSSIAN]:
[MAN GRUNTS AND GROWLS]
[SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN]
[BLADE SPEAKS IN RUSSIAN]
[IN RUSSIAN]
[English - US - SDH]